export const chapter =
  "Chapter - 12: New Political Formations in the Eighteenth Century";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What change in Mughal policy contributed to the downfall of the empire during Aurangzeb's rule?",
        optionA: "Embracing tolerance and harmony",
        optionB: "Adopting a negative attitude towards non-Muslims",
        optionC: "Establishing stronger trade relations",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was one of the consequences of Aurangzeb's policies towards non-Muslims?",
        optionA: "Increased tolerance",
        optionB: "Revolts and regional forces trying to secede",
        optionC: "Strengthening of the Mughal empire",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What event marked a deadly battle in 1761 that changed the political fortunes of India?",
        optionA: "Battle of Plassey",
        optionB: "Third Battle of Panipat",
        optionC: "Nadir Shah's invasion",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which state was earlier part of the Mughal territory and became increasingly independent without formally declaring it?",
        optionA: "Hyderabad",
        optionB: "Awadh",
        optionC: "Bengal",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was appointed as the governor of Awadh in 1722 and brought the zamindars under his control?",
        optionA: "Safdar Jung",
        optionB: "Saadat Khan",
        optionC: "Siraj-ud-daula",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question: "What was the outcome of the Battle of Plassey in 1756-57?",
        optionA: "Foundation of the Maratha Empire",
        optionB: "Establishment of English rule in India",
        optionC: "Independence of Bengal",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is credited with the expansion of the Maratha Empire across India?",
        optionA: "Shivaji",
        optionB: "Balaji Vishwanath",
        optionC: "Baji Rao I",
        correctAnswer: "c",
      },
      {
        question: "What was a notable feature of the Maratha army's movements?",
        optionA: "Heavy and slow movements",
        optionB: "Swift and often unnoticed movements",
        optionC: "Extensive paraphernalia during movements",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How did the Marathas charge revenue from territories outside their direct control?",
        optionA: "Jaziya tax",
        optionB: "Chauth",
        optionC: "Sardeshmukhi",
        correctAnswer: "b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What factor contributed to the decline of the Maratha state after the death of Surajmal?",
        optionA: "Efficient administration",
        optionB: "Peasants taking arms",
        optionC: "Inadequate attention to the army",
        correctAnswer: "c",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Awadh was earlier part of the Mughal territory. Saadat Khan, appointed as the governor in 1722, enjoyed a high mansabdari rank with a zat of ________.",
        optionA: "5,000",
        optionB: "6,000",
        optionC: "7,000",
        correctAnswer: "6,000",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Bengal, under the rule of Murshid Quli Khan, assumed independence in ________.",
        optionA: "1701",
        optionB: "1717",
        optionC: "1725",
        correctAnswer: "1717",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Hyderabad, covering parts of Telangana, Karnataka, and Maharashtra, became virtually independent in ________.",
        optionA: "1700",
        optionB: "1724",
        optionC: "1750",
        correctAnswer: "1724",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Marathas, under the leadership of Chhatrapati Shivaji, declared themselves an empire in ________.",
        optionA: "1658",
        optionB: "1674",
        optionC: "1701",
        correctAnswer: "1674",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Peshwas, who concentrated powers in their hands, set up their capital at ________.",
        optionA: "Delhi",
        optionB: "Poona (Pune)",
        optionC: "Agra",
        correctAnswer: "Poona (Pune)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Maratha army's three main parts were artillery, cavalry, and ________.",
        optionA: "Navy",
        optionB: "Air Force",
        optionC: "Infantry",
        correctAnswer: "Infantry",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Marathas charged ________ from territories outside their direct control as a promise not to raid them.",
        optionA: "Zakat",
        optionB: "Chauth",
        optionC: "Jaziya",
        correctAnswer: "Chauth",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Guru Gobind Singh shaped Sikhism as a Khalsa Panth and established a base between the ________.",
        optionA: "Yamuna and Ganges rivers",
        optionB: "Sutlej and Yamuna rivers",
        optionC: "Ganges and Brahmaputra rivers",
        correctAnswer: "Sutlej and Yamuna rivers",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Jats established an independent state of Bharatpur under the command of ________.",
        optionA: "Surajmal",
        optionB: "Badan Singh",
        optionC: "Churaman",
        correctAnswer: "Badan Singh",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Battle of Panipat in 1761 resulted in the decline of the Marathas, and the empire broke into ________ small independent kingdoms.",
        optionA: "Three",
        optionB: "Five",
        optionC: "Seven",
        correctAnswer: "Five",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Battle of Panipat in 1761 resulted in the victory of the Marathas.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Peshwas were Chitpavan Brahmin ministers who ruled the Maratha Empire from 1713 to 1761.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Awadh, Bihar, and Hyderabad were states that gained independence after struggling with the Mughals.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Guru Gobind Singh, the tenth Sikh guru, played a crucial role in shaping Sikhism as a political and military force.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Jats established an independent state of Bharatpur under the command of Raja Surajmal.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British introduced discriminatory laws that sowed the seeds of division between provinces.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The introduction of English education in India brought Indians in touch with new ideas of equality and democracy.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Marathas conducted military campaigns primarily with a focus on heavy and slow movements.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Marathas charged Sardeshmukhi from the rulers in Rajasthan as one-tenth of the revenue charged by the ruler.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The decline of the Maratha state after the death of Surajmal was due to efficient administration.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
